[speaker 0]
This railway is at the heart of a
high stakes battle between the US and China
for economic influence in Africa. It's the Banguela
railway, part of the Lobito Atlantic Railway, which
connects Angola to the heart of the copper
belt in the Democratic Republic of Congo. The
line is crucial for transporting minerals essential for
things like EV batteries and other green technologies
to the rest of the world. For years,
China has led Africa's infrastructure development, pouring 100
of 1,000,000,000 of dollars into projects like railways,
ports, and roads. But a successful US backed
bid to restore the rail line could change
power dynamics across the continent. The Banguela railway
isn't new. It was built in 1902 and
has always been crucial to Angola's trade, but
it was severely damaged during the country's civil
war. If you do go on the rail
line, you can see, some blown up armored
vehicles. You can see railcars that have been
left to rust. After the war ended, Angola
needed to rebuild its infrastructure and China stepped
in to fill that need. So in 2006,
Angola agreed to a $2,000,000,000 deal with a
group of Chinese companies to rebuild the railway
line. But poor construction and upkeep led to
rundown stations, malfunctioning safety systems, offline servers, and
frequent derailments on the train line. There's something
like 10 derailments a year, which is extraordinary.
The stations weren't well built. There's all sorts
of technological equipment that just isn't working. And
so the entire rail line really needs a
a rebuild. But this time, Angola turned down
a proposal from the Chinese government to renovate
and manage the same neglected railway. Instead, it
awarded several European companies a 30 year contract,
which the United States government is likely to
finance with a $250,000,000 loan. The 1.7000000000 dollars
project will fix the train tracks and stations,
add over 1500 wagons and educate train operators.
It will also give countries involved in the
project, eager to advance their clean energy initiatives,
greater access to on Africa in Washington at
the moment is all about on Africa in
Washington at the moment is all about critical
and strategic minerals and, and security of supply.
Demand for these elements is expected to increase
by 20 fold from 2020 to 2040, which
has fueled interest in the Lobito Corridor and
to the Democratic Republic of Congo, the world's
largest producer of cobalt. The project is expected
to be a key source of economic opportunity
for Angola's young population. So hope that they
will both feed the rest of the world
and also create jobs and opportunities inside of
Angola. Historically, you can see when you create
corridors, they attract people, especially infrastructure development. Launched
by Chinese President Xi Jinping in 2013, its
goal is to boost China's global economic influence
through infrastructure, trade and investment deals. China loaned
African governments over $160,000,000,000 from 2,000 to 2022,
and Angola has received the most. The Chinese
in Angola provided roads, railways, football stadiums, suburbs
of of of of cities. But the initiative
has faced criticism from around the world over
poor construction, environmental impact, and long term economic
sustainability. And it's left some countries with significant
debts. Those are debts that are very hard
to pay back. In a response to the
journal, the Chinese government said that the Belt
and Road Initiative was not accountable for African
debt. In recent years, China's economy has taken
a turn and investments in Africa have plummeted.
Lending dipped below $1,000,000,000 in 2022, hitting a
nearly 2 decade low. China has been looking
at its debt exposure in Africa. It hasn't
had the sort of returns that it was
expecting, and so it's a lot more risk
averse in terms of its investment portfolio. This
lull gave the US an opportunity to step
in. But the US isn't just interested in
pushing back against China's influence in the region.
It also hopes to secure key resources for
future technological advancements. Copper in particular will prove
vital as the country transitions from old style
energy production. The Biden administration has put a
focus on strengthening commercial relations with Africa. In
2022, the government set out a plan for
a modern US Africa partnership and promised to
invest $55,000,000,000 in the continent. The United States
has been traditionally behind in, doing business in
Africa. And I think the the Biden administration
is hoping that will change and is trying
to help that change. And while it is
cautious of progress made by other countries in
the region. The Biden administration has really made
a point of saying to African countries, we
understand you have long standing relations with the
Chinese, with the Russians. We're not saying you
have to give that up. But here's what
we offer and we think you'll like it.
And the offers don't stop at the Lobito
Corridor project. The US is funding solar energy
projects and other infrastructure projects in Angola. But
US investments in the region are minimal compared
to what the Chinese government has provided over
the past 20 years. Still doesn't measure up
to what the Chinese have done across Africa,
but it is a start and I think
that African countries are starting to notice that
that's happening. However, the Lobito railway project might
still benefit the Chinese. There's also a reality
that, the Lobito corridor will not exclude the
export of minerals to China along it. It's
not a monopoly railroad for the United States
and the EU. It's for free trade. And
this corridor might just be the start of
more US investment in Africa. The final blueprint
would be railroads from the Atlantic to the
Indian Ocean. And the United States is helping
fund the the research into whether that's feasible.
And who knows? Maybe someday might fund the,
you know, the project itself.