[speaker 0]
No. No. No. I don't buy it. What?
You're not a headband. You can't be here.
I tried looking you up with nothing. It's
like you don't even exist. I guess I'm
just your fantasy. So what's the biggest difference
between the real you and your occupation? By
the way, my name is Gary Johnson, and
I'm a fake hitman. I realize not everyone
fantasized about the same hitman. Every sting operation
about the same hit man. Every sting operation
was a performance. This is serious. I am
in service business. And each arrest was like
a standing ovation. Okay. Daniel Day. I headed
down to a science. Sounds lovely. Until things
got, well, run, Madison. We're expecting heavy turbulence,
so prepare to grace for him. Do I
scare you? No. Remember the lady came in
trying to have her husband kill that we
let go? No. That he let go. Yeah.
Her husband was just found dead. I'm sorry.
What happened? From my perspective, you're getting a
little sloppy. You're Gary? Who the hit man?
My name is Gary Johnson, and my simple
question for you is, who is your hit
man? We'll see. Oh lord.