[speaker 0]
Sounds like friction is something you're very familiar
with. I just it's a word just as
I feel like it's like Yes. Cast above
us right now in bold face, highlighted, underlined
letters. He's just like is growing. Friction. Yes.
Like, you're you're up in the morning, and
I imagine David Goggins going to the coffee
maker, stretching out. Good morning, sunshine. And you're
telling me from eyelids open Mhmm. There's friction.
Yes. And that is the thing that people
don't they don't fucking get. The biggest misunderstand
about David Goggins of all time. It's like
whether you believe in god or not, I
do. He put this lab rat, which is
me, on this planet. And so let me
fucking see what a beat up, abused kid
who has who can barely learn, barely learn,
Who has a twisted body, messed up messed
up genetics, sickle cell this and that. Let
me give him everything that Pretty much disqualifies
you from the military. But back then, it
wasn't extras. And and let's put them in
this and see what comes out of it.
So to do that, Friction. You don't wake
up in the morning time and go to
the coffeemaker. Matter of fact, sometimes you don't
even sleep. What it requires It's when I'm
at 2 o'clock in the it's 2 o'clock
in the morning, and my brain is thinking
about a fucking drug. And I gotta get
up and look in my book To see
what that drug is how I remember it.
And this is every day of my fucking
life. That's why when I train a fighter
or I train some I'm like, You have
no fucking idea how great you really are
because you are using such minimal minimal of
what you have. And if people can learn
to focus, this is what's possible. While it
may not be pretty, like, people wanna do
a documentary on me. I go, no. I
want to do documentary army because I will
have normal everyday people picking me apart. His
life is miserable. Who wants to live like
that? He looks it's crazy how he it's
almost like he's sick. He's psychotic. The most
frustrating thing in the world for me is
when normal people judge a man like myself
on what it really takes to extract Greatness
from nothing. It takes every bit of who
you are if you choose that route. If
you don't, Merry Christmas. Do what you gotta
do. But, yeah, all these things for me,
Like like I told you, man. I'm a
I'm a keep it real. I I'm not
coming here to talk about, like, you know,
perform without purpose. Because I go through when
I write these books, I go through and
try to dumb down David Goggins. How can
I give normal people not normal, but I
found something that most don't wanna find? How
can I speak to people and give them
something from this Crazy psychotic brain that I've
developed? How can I give him that? So
I sit down with Jennifer for years and
write down, Perform without purpose. Callous your mind.
Armor your mind. The cookie jar. The accountability
mirror. Shit that people can fucking use in
their lives. No. No. I'm glad it helps
you, But the barbaric life that I live,
that you have to live, the almost obsession
that you must have to be great, You
can't put that shit in a fucking book,
bro. You can't put it in a book.
You can't. You can't write about it. It
has to be experienced. It has to be
experienced. And you can't even after you experience
it, to write it in the book, it
would seem like He needs to be locked
up. This way. Too gory. It's it's too
gory. It doesn't make sense for a guy
that everything every second of the day, He
is trying to extract more from something. He's
constantly thinking. He's constantly constantly disciplined, never going
off the path. Whatever is injured on him,
he figures a way. It's a conqueror's mindset,
and very few people, if any, Can't really
understand what that is. Like, I'm almost 50,
and I've been this way for almost 30
years. Like, what do you do for fun?
You you would never I I I these
questions, I don't I don't get them. I
don't understand them. I don't. So yeah. I
get asked that sometimes when you, for fun,
start listening off all this stuff like podcast
and reading Right. Or working out. Right. But
So some of that resonates, but I think
what's so truly unusual about what you're describing,
your process, is that, You know, from go,
it's hard. Yep. And I have to ask
was being £300 having ascent. I'm using the
words you've described. Do it. You've said it
before. Mhmm. You had a tendency at one
point in your life early on, tell lies.
Yep. Try and get people's approval. My ass
off. Crazy haircuts, attention seeking, and and yet
all of that triggered something Mhmm. That now
is, you know, is extraordinary. Right. Do you
think those hardships were necessary to flip the
switch. I don't know if they were necessary,
but it was something that made me feel
I didn't feel good. It was easy. The
brain that I was given as a child,
It was easy to go home and think
about what how do I wanna be a
freak today? How do I wanna show up
to school today and be a freak? It
didn't require me going home and open a
book up saying, it's gonna take me all
year to learn this fucking page. So instead
of learning that page, I learned how to
become a character. And maybe that character that
I created, that 300 pound Insecure guy that
used to fake fake it till I make
it type of guy, you know, let me,
become your friend. Let me lie to you
until you like me type of guy. When
when you have any kind of any manhood,
womanhood, a human being, a soul, a spirit,
any, I had no I had I must
had just this much pride because that's exactly
what opened the door for me. Because every
day you were a character, every day you
were a clown, every day You open that
Spanish book or that science book or English
book, you like you looked at it, it
was like it looked like a foreign language.
And you're saying, where do I start? Where
who do I start? And obviously, sir. The
more I talk about it, it wasn't necessary
because what happened is I became haunted by
the mere fact that this is my existence,
And you gotta live with that. I lived
with it for a lot of years. And
so I sat back and said, okay. Alright.
I know what this takes. And when you
sit back, as fucked up as I was,
and I had a laundry list, a A
a table like this of what I have
to do to become just a human being
that can make ends meet, That can make
$1,000 a month just to get there. I
was like, oh my god, dude. Like, how
did I'm 16, 17. I can't read. I
can't write. And I oh my God. I'm
so behind the power curve, and my brain
is about Being depressed and my dad beat
my mom's not home, and kids are calling
me nigger at school. And I'm like, oh
my god, man. What the fuck do I
do? And it wasn't like someone came around
and said, hey, man. You can do this.
This is all me. Some people know where
is this cold man come from. I'm not
trying to be cold. It's the reality of
my life. It's the reality of a lot
of people's lives. And so yeah. That had
to happen for me to be haunted, to
be haunted, to pull out, to extract the
goddamn today. That haunting It's something that's still
there today. Because no matter how much you
improve, no matter how much you change who
you are, it's not permanent. You'll just wake
up and say, oh my god, man. You're
you're David Goggins. You break records. You do
this. You do that. People don't know. How
are you how are you able to just
be so hard? Can I never turn the
fucking thing off? Because once it turns off,
I go right back to the David Goggins
that is, and that's the guy that I'm
constantly fighting every day. And it's a choice,
And that choice makes you misunderstood. It makes
you crazy. That's why I hate fucking social
media. In 2013, People want me to write
my book. I did it in 2018. Took
5 years. And the reason why I didn't
do it, I set a table and Jennifer
was there. It's before I I I she
started working for me. I started dating her,
whatever. And all these people were there, And
they're like, man, you gotta go on social
media. And I was like, fuck you, man.
Like, I'm not that that's it's it's poison.
It's poison because I knew what I did
to get where I am, and I'm gonna
have these people, these normal everyday people, fat,
Lazy is exactly who I was judging me
because I know it because I was once
them. All my hard work, all my dedication,
I'm a have some normal dude get his
little brownies, little ding dong, ho ho twinkie,
Sit there with this coffee picking me apart.
Oh, he must be unhappy. He's just do
you know How hard is to put these
shoes on every damn morning? I don't have
you pick me apart? So, yeah, There's there's,
there's so much that goes into this that
I was like, fuck this. I never want
anything to do with it.