[speaker 0]
An ability to control your levels of stress
in real time is extremely powerful. It turns
out you can do this using physiology and
neuroscience. Your breathing can directly impact your heart
rate and your level of stress or calm.
Here's how it works. When you inhale, your
diaphragm moves down. This creates more space in
your thoracic cavity, and your heart actually gets
a little bit bigger. As a consequence, the
rate of blood flow through that larger heart
volume slows down. A signal is sent from
a group of neurons on your heart called
the sinoatrial node. That signal goes up to
the brain, and your brain sends a signal
to speed the heart up. In other words,
inhaling speeds your heart rate up. The opposite
is true as well. When you exhale, your
diaphragm moves up. Your heart gets a little
bit smaller because there's a little bit less
space in your thoracic cavity. As a consequence,
blood flows more quickly through that smaller volume.
The sinoatrial node registers that and sends a
signal to your brain, and the brain sends
a signal to slow the heart down. So
in other words, inhaling speeds your heart rate
up, exhaling slows your heart rate down. So
if you want to speed up your heart
rate and be more alert, Inhale more or
make those inhales more vigorous, more intense. If
you wanna calm down, You can do that
quickly by making your exhale slightly longer than
your inhales or making them more vigorous. This
doesn't require any breath work. This is something
that you can do in real time. And
that's what's called respiratory sinus arrhythmia. That's the
technical phrase. It's also the basis of what's
called heart rate variability or HRV. But all
you need to remember is inhaling deeper and
longer will speed your heart rate up. Exhaling
Longer and more intensely will slow your heart
rate down and will allow you to calm
down in